FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Skilled in writing clean, testable UI code. Experienced with React, jQuery, Node, vanilla JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to pick up the right tools for the job.

Key Skills

Advanced: JavaScript, React, jQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs

Proficient: MongoDB and PostgreSQL; Responsive mobile-first design; TDD with Mocha, Chai, and Enzyme; ES6

Foreign Language: Hebrew-fluent, Spanish-advanced, French-proficient, Portuguese-proficient

Experience

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, 9/2017 -- Present

Recent Projects

Subscribr: Full stack app for managing subscriptions. Built with React & Redux, Node, Express and PostgreSQL.

Christmas List: Holiday shopping list app. Built with React.

BURLINGTON ENGLISH | Tel Aviv, Israel

English Instructor, 9/2016 - 9/2017

- Provided instruction in English grammar, speaking, and composition to adult individuals and groups.
- Devised personalized and engaging lesson plans tailored to individuals' needs and interests, maximizing student engagement and retention of material.
- Instructed junior teachers in effective vs. ineffective pedagogical techniques.
- Supplied feedback to students on progress and made recommendations for more effective individual study.

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON | Madison, WI

Language Specialist, 5/2014 - 9/2016

- Transcribed, normalized, translated, and catalogued Yiddish-, Hebrew-, and Slavic-language materials for the Mayrent Project, aimed at preserving Eastern European Jewish music and culture.
- Managed and edited a database of collected materials.
- Deciphered and catalogued books in various unidentified languages written in Perso-Arabic script, such as Uyghur and Kazakh.

Education

THINKFUL

Engineering Immersion, Expected 2/2018

- Intensive full-time course on modern full-stack JavaScript development.
- Learning industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON

Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics & Modern Hebrew, 5/2014

GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

- Graduated with distinction
- ФВК Honor Society inductee